{
    "Air Law and Legislation":[
        {
            "question":"The Chicago Convention was signed in _____. This led to the formation of ICAO which is based in _____.",
            "answers": ["1944, Montreal", "1943, Qubec", "1944 Chicago", "1948, Montreal"],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The principals of the ICAO as laid down by the Chicago Convention are known as _____.",
            "answers": ["Annexes", "Articles", "Addendums", "Parts"],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Definitive documents relating to the ICAO Articles are known as _____.",
            "answers":["Annexes", "Articles", "Addendums", "Parts"],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Each nation (State) that has signed the Chicago Convention (has/has not) exclusive sovereignty over the airspace above its territory.",
            "answers": ["has", "has not"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"A State's sovereignty over its territory (is/is not) considered the waters adjacent to its land areas.",
            "answers":["is", "is not"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"Other than scheduled international flights, a member State (will/will not) allow aircraft from another State to fly into or through its airspace and onto land without prior permission.",
            "answers":["will", "will not"],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question":"Irrespective of its nationality an aircraft on an international flight (should/must) obey the regulations of the overflown State.",
            "answers":["should", "must"],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question":"An aircraft operating within a State's territory must follow the rules of the air. Over the high seas these rules (do/do not) apply.",
            "answers":["do", "do not"],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question":"Each State (does/does not) have the right to search aircraft from other States on landing or prior to departure.",
            "answers":["does", "does not"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"Each State (may/may not) require aircraft entering its territory to land at a customs airport for a customs examination unless the flight has permission to cross its territory without landing.",
            "answers":["may", "may not"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"Aircraft (do/do not) have the nationality of the State in which they are registered.",
            "answers": ["do", "do not"],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question":"Under the terms of the Chicago Convention each contracting State has:",
            "answers":["Shared sovereignty over the airspace above its land and territorial waters.", "Exclusive sovereignty over the airspace above its land borders.",
                "Exclusive sovereignty over the airspace above its land and territorial waters.","Exclusive sovereignty over airspace above its land borders and shared sovereignty over the airspace above its territorial waters."],
            "correct":2
        },
        {
            "question": "With regard to the Chicago Convention, an aircraft entering the territory of a contracting State:",
            "answers": ["May be required to land at a customs airport.", "Is always required to land at a customs airport.", 
                "May be required to land at a port of entry.", "May be required to land and an immigration airport."],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question": "Aircraft (may/may not) be registered in more than one State.",
            "answers": ["may", "may not"],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question":"Aircraft operating internationally (should/must) display approapriate nationality and registration marks.",
            "answers": ["should","must"],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question":"ICAO requires that an aircraft on an international flight must carry:",
            "answers":["The Certificate of Airworthiness, Certificate of Registration and the latest Certificate of Maintenance Review.",
                "The Certificate of Airworthiness, Certificate of Registration, Crew Licences and a journey log book.",
                "The Certificate of Airworthiness, a current weight and balance and aircraft radio licences.",
                "The Certificate of Airworthiness, Certificate of Registration, Crew Licences, a journey log book, appropriate radio licences and, if applicable, passenger and cargo manifests."],
            "correct":3
        },
        {
            "question":"To operate radio transmitting equipment over the territory of a contracting State:",
            "answers":["The radio operator must be licensed by the state of registry of the aircraft.",
                "The radio station must be licensed by the state of registry of the aircraft.",
                "Both the radio station and the operator must be licensed by the state of registry of the aircraft.",
                "Either the radio station or the operator must be licensed by the state of registry of the aircraft."],
            "correct":2
        },
        {
            "question":"Each contracting ICAO State:",
            "answers":["Must gain the permission of the operator in advance before an aircraft is searched.",
                "Has the right to search and aircraft from other States on landing and prior to departure to inspect documents.",
                "Has no right to search aircraft from another State.",
                "Has the right to search aircraft from other States if it is suspected that they are carrying illegal substances."],
            "correct":1
        },
        {
            "question":"Pink coloured AICs contain information relating to:",
            "answers":["Administrative matters.","Ait Traffic Services.","UK restrictions charts.","Air safety."],
            "correct":3
        },
        {
            "question":"A NOTAMC:",
            "answers":["Contains information relating to a class C hazard to air navigation.",
                "Contains new information, and is the third NOTAM issued on a particular day.",
                "Cancels a previous NOTAM.",
                "Continues a previous NOTAM."],
            "correct":2
        },
        {
            "question":"Aircraft landing in another State's territory (is/is not) normally exampt from customs duty on fuel, oil, spare parts and stores that were on board on arival and are retained on board on departure.",
            "answers":["is", "is not"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"Spare parts imported into a State for use by an aircraft from another State on international operations (will/ will not) be free from duty.",
            "answers": ["will","will not"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"Should an aircraft registered in one State be involved in an accident in another State, the State in which the accident occurs (shall/ shall not) run an inquiry.",
            "answers": ["shall", "shall not"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"Should an aircraft registered in one State be involved in an accident in another State, the State in which the aircraft is registered (shall/ shall not) be allowed to observe the inquiry.",
            "answers": ["shall", "shall not"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"For aircraft that have failed to meet any international standard of airworthiness at certification:",
            "answers":["Shall show on its certification of airworthiness, full details of any failure(s).",
                "Shall show on its certification of airworthiness, details of any failure(s) if not rectified within 3 months.",
                "Is not required to show details of any failure(s).",
                "Shall show on its certification of airworthiness, details of any failure(s) if not rectified within 6 months."],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question": "What does ICAO stand for?",
            "answers": ["International Civil Aviation Organization", "International Civil Air Operations", "International Correspondence for Air Operations",
                "International Communication for Aviation Organizations"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"Official information regarding The Rules of the Air nd Air Traffic Services is found in the _____ section of the UK __________.",
            "answers": ["ENR, UK Aeronautical Information publication", "GEN, UK Aeronautical Information publication", 
                    "AD, UK Aeronautical Information publication", "Pink, UK Air Information Circular"],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning Aeronautical Information Circulars (AICs), the Air Safety AICs are usually printed on _____ coloured paper.",
            "answers": ["pink", "green", "white", "mauve"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning Aeronautical Information Circulars (AICs), the Administrative AICs are usually printed on _____ coloured paper.",
            "answers": ["pink", "yellow", "white", "mauve"],
            "correct":2
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning Aeronautical Information Circulars (AICs), the Operational and Air Traffic Services AICs are usually printed on _____ coloured paper.",
            "answers": ["green", "yellow", "white", "mauve"],
            "correct":1
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning Aeronautical Information Circulars (AICs), the UK Restrictions Charts AICs are usually printed on _____ coloured paper.",
            "answers": ["pink", "yellow", "green", "mauve"],
            "correct":3
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning Aeronautical Information Circulars (AICs), the Maps/Charts AICs are usually printed on _____ coloured paper.",
            "answers": ["green", "yellow", "white", "mauve"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC 127(P 110)/2006: A 10% increase in weight will increase the take-off distance to height 50 ft by ___.",
            "answers": ["20% (factor 1.2)", "25% (factor 1.25)", "10% (factor 1.1)", "30% (factor 1.3)"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC 127(P 110)/2006: A Tailwind Component of 10% of Lift-off Speed will increase the take-off distance to height 50 ft by ___.",
            "answers": ["20% (factor 1.2)", "25% (factor 1.25)", "10% (factor 1.1)", "30% (factor 1.3)"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC 127(P 110)/2006: An increase of 10°C in Ambient Temperature will increase the take-off distance to height 50 ft by ___.",
            "answers": ["20% (factor 1.2)", "25% (factor 1.25)", "10% (factor 1.1)", "30% (factor 1.3)"],
            "correct":2
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC 127(P 110)/2006: Wet Grass- Up to 20 cm (8 in) (on firm soil) will increase the take-off distance to height 50 ft by ___.",
            "answers": ["20% (factor 1.2)", "25% (factor 1.25)", "10% (factor 1.1)", "30% (factor 1.3)"],
            "correct":3
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC 127(P 110)/2006: A Wet paved runway will increase the landing distance to height 50 ft by ___.",
            "answers": ["10% (factor 1.1)", "5% (factor 1.05)", "35% (factor 1.35)", "25% or more (factor 1.25+)"],
            "correct":2
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC 127(P 110)/2006: Wet Grass- Up to 20 cm (8 in) (on firm soil) will increase the landing distance to height 50 ft by ___.",
            "answers": ["10% (factor 1.1)", "5% (factor 1.05)", "35% (factor 1.35)", "25% or more (factor 1.25+)"],
            "correct":2
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC 127(P 110)/2006: Snow will increase the landing distance to height 50 ft by ___.",
            "answers": ["10% (factor 1.1)", "5% (factor 1.05)", "35% (factor 1.35)", "25% or more (factor 1.25+)"],
            "correct":3
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC P 083/2020: A light aircraft departing behind a heavy aircraft using the full length of the same runway should leave _____ for the dispersal of wake turbulence.",
            "answers": ["3 minutes", "2 minutes", "4 nm or equivilent time", "No wake turbulence seperation minima required."],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC P 083/2020: A small aircraft departing behind a heavy aircraft but departing from an intermediate part of the same runway should leave _____ for the dispersal of wake turbulence.",
            "answers": ["3 minutes", "2 minutes", "4 nm or equivilent time", "No wake turbulence seperation minima required."],
            "correct":1
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC P 083/2020: A light aircraft departing behind a small aircraft but departing from an intermediate part of the same runway should leave _____ for the dispersal of wake turbulence.",
            "answers": ["3 minutes", "2 minutes", "4 nm or equivilent time", "No wake turbulence seperation minima required."],
            "correct":1
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC P 083/2020: A medium aircraft departing behind a super aircraft using the full length of the same runway should leave _____ for the dispersal of wake turbulence.",
            "answers": ["3 minutes", "2 minutes", "4 nm or equivilent time", "No wake turbulence seperation minima required."],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC P 083/2020: Unless alternative wake turbulence separation criteria have been approved for use, the UK wake turbulence separation minima are applied when",
            "answers": ["An aircraft is operating directly behind another aircraft at the same altitude or less than 1000 FT below.", 
                    "An aircraft is crossing behind another aircraft at the same altitude or less than 1000 FT below.", 
                    "Both aircraft are using the same runway or parallel runways separated by less than 760 M (2500 FT)", 
                    "All cases mentioned."],
            "correct":3
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC P 083/2020: A light aircraft landing behind a heavy aircraft should leave _____ for the dispersal of wake turbulence.",
            "answers": ["3 minutes.", 
                    "7nm (6nm ICAO)", 
                    "4nm (4nm ICAO)", 
                    "6nm (7nm ICAO)"],
            "correct":1
        },
        {
            "question": "Concerning AIC P 083/2020: A small aircraft landing behind a lower medium aircraft should leave _____ for the dispersal of wake turbulence.",
            "answers": ["3 minutes.", 
                    "7nm (6nm ICAO)", 
                    "4nm (4nm ICAO)", 
                    "3nm"],
            "correct":3
        },
        {
            "question": "A pilot should not fly for at least _____ after taking small amounts of alcohol, and proportionally longer if larger amounts are consumed.",
            "answers": ["8 hours", 
                    "6 hours", 
                    "24 hours", 
                    "12 hours"],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question": "AVGAS filler points should be painted _____ to avoid confusion with turbine filler points.",
            "answers": ["Red", "Orange", "Black", "Red/Orange and White"],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "AVTUR filler points should be painted _____ to avoid confusion with gasoline filler points.",
            "answers": ["Red", "Orange", "Black", "Red/Orange and White"],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The Air Navigation Order (ANO) is sub-divided into _____ which consist of _____ numbered consecutively.",
            "answers": ["Parts, Articles", "Parts, appendices", "Chapters, Sections", "Chapters, Articles"],
            "correct": 0
        }


    ],
    "Rules of the Air": [
        {
            "question":"The ultimate responsibility for taking all possible measures to avoid collision between aircraft lies with:",
            "answers":["Air Traffic Control.", "The Pilot-in-Command.","The most highly qualified pilot on board.","The Air/Ground Communications Operator."],
            "correct":1
        },
        {
            "question":"In the air, when two aircraft are approaching head on, or approximetly so:",
            "answers":["Each aircraft will alter course to the right in order to pass well clear.",
                "Each aircraft will alter course to the left in order to pass well clear.",
                "The aircraft with greater speed has right of way.",
                "The aircraft may turn left or right accroding to the perticular cirumstances in order to pass well clear."],
            "correct":0
        },
        {
            "question":"The minimum height to fly over the congested areas of cities, towns or settlements or over an open-air assembly of persons is:",
            "answers":["600 m (2,000 ft) above the heighest obstacle within a radius of 600 m from the aircraft.",
                "300 m (1,000 ft) above the heighest obstacle within a radius of 600 m from the aircraft.",
                "600 m (2,000 ft) above the heighest obstacle within a radius of 300 m from the aircraft.",
                "300 m (1,000 ft) above the heighest obstacle within a radius of 300 m from the aircraft."],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "In relation to converging aircraft in the air, the correct order is:",
            "answers":["Balloons ,ust give way to airships ans sailplanes.",
                "Sailplanes must give way to powered aircraft, airships, and balloons.",
                "Powered aircraft must give way to airships, sailplanes and balloons.",
                "Airships must give way to powered aircraft, sailplanes and balloons."],
            "correct":2
        }
    ]

}